看看我给大家带什么来了
Hey! Look what I got everybody.
报纸吗
Newspapers?
你是找到回90年代的传送门了吗
Did you find a portal back to the 1990s?
不是  如果他有这能耐  早就回去阻止
No. If he had that, he'd be trying to prevent NSYNC
超级男孩的解散了
from breaking up.
拜托  我很庆幸他们解散了
Oh, please. I'm glad they broke up.
不然成员贾斯丁就不会让"性感回归[作品]"了
Otherwise, Justin would never have brought sexy back.
平板电脑永远不会有的东西
One thing you can't get on an iPad,
墨水和纸张的味道
the smell of ink and paper.
又多了一个平板电脑更好的理由
One more reason iPads are better.
他们评论了我的天文台节目
They reviewed my planetarium show.
就在艺术与休闲版的第三页
Yeah. It's on page three of the Arts and Leisure section.
看  居然还在刊登知名讽刺漫画《远端》
Oh, look, they still have Far Side.
这个笑话我没懂
Oh, I don't get that one.
他应该是要拉而不是推
Oh, he's pushing when he should be pulling.
那我觉得他不应该去上那家天才学校
I don't think he belongs in that gifted school, then.
-你在干嘛  -折纸船
- What are you doing? - Making a boat.
我小时候我爸教我折的
When I was a kid, my dad showed me how.
天啊  为了逃避阅读  你真是花样百出
Boy, you'll do anything to avoid reading.
各位  是在"周末可做的活动"栏位里
Guys, it's under "Things to do this weekend."
我找不到啊  写了什么
I can't find it. What does it say?
说值得周末去看一下
That it's a thing to do this weekend.
很棒啊  拉杰  恭喜你啊
That's great, Raj. Congratulations.
趁着在互相显摆
You know, while we're bragging,
《假体医学期刊》
The Journal of Prosthetic Medicine
报道了我跟霍华德一起合作的项目呢
just wrote up the project that Howard and I are working on.
你没跟我说过啊
Well, you didn't tell me that.
才刚出啦  就一小段而已
Oh, it just came out. It's just a little blurb.
恭喜你啊
Oh, well, good for you.
我跟伯特也开始了从陨石中
You know, Bert and I have started isolating zircons
孤立出皓石来进行暗物质的研究
from meteorites for our dark matter search.
很棒啊
Oh. Well, how nice.
大家最近的工作都好棒棒啊
Everyone's doing impressive work.
那你最近都在做些什么研究呢
What have you been working on these days?
哎哟喂  这一枪是从哪打来的
Whoa, whoa. Where'd that come from?
什么枪是哪里打来
Where did what come from?
我尽量地支持大家
I try to be supportive,
你却直接对我严刑逼供
and you break out the hot lights and the rubber hose.
我只是问了你最近在研究什么
I just asked what you've been working on.
要命了  别问了好吗
Oh, my God, let it go.
你看这人
Do you believe this guy?
我成功啦
I did it!
看到没  是一艘船
See? It's a... it's a boat.
还是一顶帽子呢
It's also a hat.
第十一季  第十三集
来吧  你想怎么来
Okay, how do you want to play this?
是假装你没有任何烦心事
Do you want to pretend like nothing's bothering you
然后之后突然爆发  还是你干脆一点
and blow up later, or do you just want to be
现在就开始发疯
a maniac right now?
我没有烦心事啊
Nothing is bothering me.
行  那就这么着
Fine. Be that way.
但如果你想聊  我就在旁边洗鼻子
If you want to talk, I'll be flushing my sinuses.
等等
Wait.
我有件事想坦白
I have a confession.
当我怒斥莱纳德时
When I berated Leonard,
其实那是我巧妙地掩盖
it was a clever ruse to conceal the fact
我最近屁事儿都没干的烟幕弹
that I'm not working on anything.
我觉得我的话能代表大家的心声
Well, I think I speak for everyone
那就是"真的假的"
when I say, "No!"
其实我最近没有任何感兴趣的项目
The truth is I have nothing of interest to pursue.
或许现在是个很棒的机会
Well, maybe this is the perfect opportunity
来沉淀自己  重新找到方向
to take some time for yourself and refocus.
我相信你一定能找到你感兴趣的研究方向
I'm sure you'll find something you're excited about.
谢谢你  艾米
Thank you, Amy.
没有你我真不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'd do without you.
我能待在这里吗  谢尔顿把我踢出来了
Hey, can I stay here? Sheldon kicked me out.
没事吧
Well, is everything okay?
没事啦  他只是想独处做些工作
Yeah. He just wants some alone time to work.
那好  当自己家吧
Fine. Make yourself at home.
对啊  我们正打算看点电视节目
Yeah. We were just about to watch a little TV.
欢迎你跟我们一起看啊
You're welcome to join us.
谢谢  我马上过来看
Thanks. I'll be right with you.
等我先洗一下鼻子就行
I just have to, uh, do my neti pot.
你们打算看什么呢
So what are you guys gonna watch?
好了
Okay.
你觉得我们开场应该用哪首歌
Hey, uh, what do you think we should open our show with?
"雷神索尔与博士琼斯"
Uh, "Thor and Doctor Jones"
还是"更太空物理[亲密]点吧"
or "Let's Get Astrophysical"?
不知道了  我觉得开场应该用
I don't know. I think we should start with something
会让他们站起来的热血歌曲
that gets them up on their feet.
或许"马不停蹄夏洛克"吧
Maybe "Sherlock Around the Clock."
不错  有道理  来试试
Great, yeah. Uh, let's give it a try.
哈雷在午睡  小声点
Halley's napping! Keep it down!
好  对不起
Oh. Right. Sorry.
没事  我们摇滚不靠大声
It's cool. We don't need volume to rock.
不用把屋顶嗨到掀飞
Instead of blowing the roof off this place,
我们就温柔地举起屋顶
we can gently lift it off
再轻轻将它放到后院
and set it quietly down in the backyard.
好
Okay.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
♪ 福尔摩斯对华生说话 ♪
♪ Holmes said to Watson ♪
♪ 在他们贝克街 ♪
♪ On Baker Street ♪
♪ 出发吧  医生 ♪
♪ Come on, Doctor ♪
♪ 是时候该出发了 ♪
♪ Time to move them feet ♪
跟我们一起唱
Sing it with us.
♪ 夏洛克  夏洛克 ♪
♪ Sherlock, Sherlock ♪
♪ 马不停蹄夏洛克 ♪
♪ Sherlock around the clock ♪
再唱大声点
We can't hear you.
♪ 夏洛克  夏洛克 ♪
♪ Sherlock, Sherlock ♪
♪ 马不停蹄夏洛克 ♪
♪ Sherlock around the clock ♪
干得漂亮啊
Nice going.
对不起  抱歉  我去哄她
Sorry. Sorry. I'll get her.
稍等
One sec.
你买尿布了  对吧
You bought diapers, right?
马上回来
Be right back.
摇滚万岁
Rock and roll!
好的  草稿纸  有了
Okay. Scratch paper, check.
白板  有了
Whiteboard, check.
综合零嘴  有了
Chex Mix, check.
正式开始
And here we go.
靠
Oh, dang it.
你好啊  妈妈
Hello, Mother.
你好啊  谢利  你绝对想不到
Hi there, Shelly. You will never believe
烧烤节上我遇见谁了
who I ran into at the barbecue festival.
我正忙着很重要的工作呢
I am right in the middle of some very important work.
我现在没空聊这些有的没的
I don't have time for this right now.
那你为什么接我电话
Then why did you answer the phone?
因为你教育我做人要有礼貌
Because you raised me to be polite.
不要再打扰我了
Now stop bothering me.
再次问好
Hello again.
你在烧烤节上遇到谁了
Who did you see at the barbecue festival?
沃特金斯先生
Mr. Watkins.
不是吧
Really?
你在我工作到一半的时候打电话打扰我
You called me and interrupted my work to tell me
就为了这个你本来就有可能遇到的人吗
that you ran into somebody you could plausibly run into?
对不起  妈  我真的得专心工作了
I'm sorry, Mother, I really need to focus here.
我下周再跟您联系
I will speak to you next week.
好  亲爱的  我们下周聊
Okay, sweetheart. I'll talk to you then.
沃特金斯先生不是搬去佛罗里达了吗
I thought Mr. Watkins moved to Florida.
是啊  他回来看他儿子
He did. He was back visiting his son.
要亲命了  还真是有趣
Oh, gosh darn it, that is interesting.
是看汤米还是看乔
Was it Tommy or Joe?
应该是看乔吧  他跟汤米因为
I bet it was Joe, 'cause he and Tommy had a falling out
分时度假的事闹了不愉快
over that time-share.
你们昨天晚餐后有做什么好玩的事吗
You guys do anything fun after dinner?
艾米后来又回我家  我们一起玩了
Well, actually Amy came back over and we hung out.
你知道我们都曾是拼字比赛冠军吗
Did you know that we're both spelling bee champs?
我们熬了好几个小时试图打败对方
We stayed up for hours trying to stump each other.
谁赢了
Who won?
她以为她能用花音[装饰音的一种]打败我
Oh, she thought she had me with "Appoggiatura,"
但我以迅雷不及掩耳之势灭了她
but I shut that down expeditiously.
卂辶雨田不及扌奄耳之执力
E-x-p-e-d-i-t-i-o-u-s-l-y.
迅雷不及掩耳之势
Expeditiously.
我猜你"威猛"的样子让佩妮宽衣解带
I bet that made Penny take off all of her clothes.
再换上睡衣早早睡觉去了吧
Put her pajamas on and then go to bed early.
对啊  九点就去睡了
At, like, 9:00.
我们今晚还练团吗
Oh, are we still on for band practice this evening?
我靠
Oh, shoot.
我答应了带哈雷去我岳父岳母家
I promised I would take Halley over to Bernadette's parents.
-兄弟  表演就在下周末呢  -我知道
- Dude, the gig is, like, next weekend. - I know.
对不起  我真的很想好好演出
I'm sorry. I really want to do this,
但我好像真的没有时间
but I just don't think I have the time.
好吧  那我可能只能取消演出了
Okay. I-I guess I'll have to cancel.
托比·格林鲍姆不能在我们的加持下长大了
Toby Greenbaum will have to become a man without us.
太可惜了  你们可是成年礼之王啊
Too bad, you guys kill at bar mitzvahs.
在其他观众不能随意离开的活动也是一霸
And other events that people can't leave.
我不想成为拆散乐队的人
I don't want to be the one who breaks up the band.
但或许你应该...
You know, maybe you should...
想想找谁来代替我
think about replacing me.
-好啊  -我意思是
- Okay. - I mean,
我知道这很难  因为我们...
I know it'll be hard since we...
我觉得伯特能行  他会弹吉他
Oh, I bet Bert could do it. He plays guitar.
我去问问他
I'm gonna go ask him.
我猜他忘了我会拉大提琴
I guess he forgot that I play the cello.
我觉得他并没有忘
I-I don't think he did.
好了  我觉得已经准备就绪
Okay, I think it's ready.
我们要戴护目镜吗
Should we put on safety goggles?
最安全的乐子就是最有趣的乐子  当然戴
Well, the funnest fun is the safest fun, so yes.
艾米你又...  返场啦
Oh, Amy, you're here... again.
谢尔顿说他需要再多一晚独处工作
Yeah, Sheldon said he needed another night to work,
所以我就说那我给他空间
so I said I'd give him some space.
这是在干嘛
So what's all this?
我跟艾米在聊以前做过的科学展览报告
Well, Amy and I were talking about old science fair projects,
然后就想到重新做一次会多有意思
and how fun it would be to recreate them.
我们要做热冰
We're making hot ice.
很酷[冷]
It's pretty cool.
好哏
Nice one.
我们发现我们两人
Turns out we both did this
都为九年级的科学展览报告做了这个
as our science fair projects in ninth grade.
你还记得你高中时期做过什么吗
Do you remember any of your high school projects?
我还记得跟珍妮·鲁尼恩说
Uh, well, I remember telling Jenny Runyon
我愿意教她怎么勾引男生
that I would teach her how to flirt with boys
只要她在科学报告上写我名字就行
if she put my name on her project.
我喜获了"A"  她喜获麟儿
I got an "A," She got pregnant.
你这样的女孩害我放学得立刻回家
Girls like you are why I had to come straight home after school.
看好了
Check this out.
我看看
Look at that.
这好厉害啊
Wow, that's amazing.
它的结晶是一种放热过程
The crystallization is an exothermic process,
所以这个冰是热的
so the ice is actually hot.
-这作品让我得了第一  -我也是
- I won first place for this. - So did I.
我为珍妮举办了迎婴派对
I threw Jenny's baby shower.
七年级的时候
Oh, hey, in seventh grade,
我做了眼镜蛇波  你想来做这个吗
I built a cobra wave. You want to do that?
我们可以想出波速公式
Oh, we can come up with a wave speed formula,
看看我们能多精准地预测它的振幅
and see how accurately we can predict the amplitude.
哇  我还以为昨晚的
Wow, I didn't think anything could top
拼字大赛已经登峰造极  但数学更无聊一筹啊
last night's spelling bee, but here comes math.
抱歉  我们可以不继续做实验
I'm sorry, we-we don't have to do more experiments.
来做点我们大家都喜欢做的事吧
Let's do something we can all enjoy.
你想来看你喜欢的那个节目
Hey, uh, you want to watch that show you like
就是有人想买房子  然后就去买了的节目吗
where people want to buy a house and then they do?
不不不  你们做实验吧
No, no, you guys do your experiments.
我去带晚饭回来
I'll go pick up dinner.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
对啊  你们在享受科学
Yeah, you're having science fun,
我不想打扰你们  也不想看
and I don't want to interfere, or watch you.
我真的算出来了吗
Did I actually do it?
真的耶  真的
I did. I did.
答案是1800万分之一
The answer is one in 18 million.
什么东西是
What is?
你遇见沃特金斯先生的几率啊
The odds of you running into Mr. Watkins.
谢利  我有个坏消息
Oh, Shelly. I have bad news.
沃特金斯先生今早去世了
Mr. Watkins passed this morning.
我很遗憾
Oh, I'm-I'm sorry.
是啊  得什么几率才碰到这种事啊
I know. What are the odds of that?
晚点打给你
Call you back.
现在我们来计算振幅吧
Now let's calculate the amplitude!
好哒
All right!
谢尔顿  谢尔顿  谢尔顿
Sheldon? Sheldon? Sheldon?
你学我这么敲时很烦人
It's annoying when you do it.
我给你带了披萨
I brought pizza.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
我一直在埋头苦干
I have been working pretty hard.
也该休息一下了
I-I could use a break.
那是什么
What's that?
那个啊  是一个实验
Oh, yeah, that is an experiment
看看我憋着气不呼吸时
to see how many parallelograms I could draw
能画几个平行四边形
while holding my breath.
你是在那个地方昏过去的吗
Is that where you blacked out?
不  其实
No, actually,
那里才是我真正昏过去的地方
that's where I blacked out.
这个呢
And this?
这是一张清单
That is a list
上面列出了全部不同类型的自然灾害
of all the different types of natural disasters.
"火震"
"Fire-quake"?
那个是我瞎编的
I made that one up.
其实我不该这么做  现在我害怕它真会发生
Which I shouldn't have, because now I'm scared of it.
我还以为你研究的是真正的科学呢
Hey, I thought you were working on actual science.
是啊
I am.
我试图想出研究暗物质的新思路
I'm trying to come up with a new approach to dark matter,
但总有人让我分心
but people keep distracting me.
首先是我妈  我一打电话她就接
First, my mother kept answering the phone when I called,
即便她知道我忙得不行
even though she knew I was busy.
而现在你又带着我最喜欢的形状食物出现
And now you show up with my favorite shape of food--
由三角形组成的圆形被装进正方形的盒子里
a circle made of triangles served in a square box.
要不我还是去洗衣房吃算了
Maybe I'll just eat this in the laundry room.
别别  等等
No, no. Wait.
你不用走
You don't have to go,
你只要乖乖坐好别出声就行
as long as you sit quietly and don't say anything.
好吧
Fine.
好吃
Good.
你是在模仿嘲讽我吗
Are you mocking me?
on the nose[在鼻子上/说对了]
你想不想听我其中一首地质学歌
Hey, you want to hear one of my geology songs?
是关于岩石的吗
So it's about rocks?
比这厉害多了  是关于巨石的
Better. It's about a boulder.
本质不都是石头吗
Isn't that the same thing?
远非如此
Far from it.
巨石的直径通常大于25.6厘米
A boulder has a diameter greater than 25.6 centimeters.
这知识也在那歌里吗
Is that fact in the song?
没有
No.
有啦
Yes.
《夺宝奇兵1》中曾出现主角被巨石穷追不舍的经典桥段
歌词唱的是追赶
It's sung from the viewpoint of the boulder
印第安纳·琼斯的那块巨石
that chases Indiana Jones.
那正好符合我们的风格  唱来听听吧
That's right up our alley. Let's hear it.
♪ 秘鲁深处  独守古庙 ♪
♪ Alone in my temple in the middle of Peru ♪
♪ 巨石如我  无事可做 ♪
♪ A giant stone ball with nothing much to do ♪
♪ 谁敢偷我神像 ♪
♪ But if you steal my idol ♪
♪ 直接把你压扁 ♪
♪ I will roll right over you ♪
♪ 因为我是六吨重的花岗岩和云母片岩 ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm six tons of granite and micaceous schist ♪
♪ 没错  六吨重的花岗岩 ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm six tons of granite and ♪
♪ 和云母片岩 ♪
♪ Micaceous schist ♪
♪ 因为我是六吨重的花岗岩和云母片岩 ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm six tons of granite and, uh, micaceous schist ♪
♪ 没错  六吨重的花岗岩 ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm six tons of granite ♪
♪ 和云母片岩 ♪
♪ And, uh, micaceous schist ♪
我觉得如果想预测起伏的高度
So, I think if we want to predict the height of the wave,
我们需要用到弹性理论
we need to use elasticity theory
还要将格架作为
and model the lattice
一个连续柔性块的模型
as one continuous flexible piece.
这真有意思
This is fun.
一边玩冰棒棍
Playing with Popsicle sticks,
一边探索存储动能的方式
exploring ways to store kinetic energy.
仿佛又回到了幼儿园
It's like preschool all over again.
除了现在如果我要吃浆糊  是因为我想吃
Except now if I eat paste, it's because I want to,
而不是因为克雷格·舒尔茨逼我
not because Craig Schultz is making me.
我能问你个问题吗
Hey, can I ask you a question?
是要问"当时老师在哪儿"吗
Is it, "Where was the teacher?"
她在洗手间抽烟呢  就是那儿
She was in the bathroom smoking, that's where.
不是啦  不过我很高兴你走出阴霾了
It wasn't, but I'm glad to see you've moved on.
我本来是要问  结婚不结婚有什么不一样
I was gonna ask if being married felt any different.
好像...没什么不一样
Oh. Uh... not really.
抱歉  这可能不是你想听到的答案
Sorry. That probably wasn't the answer you were looking for.
不  恰恰就是
No, actually it is.
我的意思是  我和谢尔顿现在的感情非常好
I mean, Sheldon and I are in a really great place right now,
我不想让任何事情破坏它
and I just, I don't want anything to mess that up.
你没忘记你之所以在这儿
You do remember you're here
是因为他把你从你们家踢出来吧
because he kicked you out of your apartment?
没忘啊
Yes.
他的工作对他很重要
His work is important to him.
这正是我觉得他
It's one of the things I find
性感的地方之一
the sexiest about him.
这个还有...
Well, that and...
他的小翘臀
...his butt.
那时我在考虑要不要
And then I was thinking about
创造一种新的暗物质粒子
inventing a new dark matter particle
避开Ω粒子约束
to evade the omega baryon constraints,
但那没难度  感觉随便一个人都能想出来
but that just seems like something anyone could come up with.
同意
Agreed.
你知道什么让我惊讶吗
You know what's blowing my mind?
居然有人想出把芝士塞进披萨边里
Somebody thought about putting cheese in this crust.
我就是希望我能找到能引起我兴趣的事物
I just wish I could find something that excites me.
你能理解通常披萨边里面
You do understand that crust doesn't normally
是不会有芝士的吧
come with cheese in it?
好吧好吧  听着
Okay, all right, look.
暗物质一开始是哪点吸引了你的兴趣
What got you excited about dark matter in the first place?
当时我放弃了弦理论
Well, I left string theory,
那个方向其实我已经研究了很长时间了
which I'd been working on for a long time,
人人都在谈论暗物质有多酷
and everyone was talking about how cool dark matter was,
于是我就想  "行吧  我来试试"
and I thought, "Well, sure, I'll give that a whirl"
所以它是你的备胎科学
So it's your rebound science?
什么意思
What's that?
意思就是  暗物质不是你想共度余生的科学
Well, not the science you spend the rest of your life with,
只是能让你重新自我感觉良好
but the one you use to make yourself feel pretty again.
如果要我老实说
Well, if I'm being honest,
其实我从没忘掉过弦理论
I never forgot about string theory.
它太出色了
It's remarkable.
它是目前我们最接近能解释一切的一种理论
It's the closest we've come to a theory of everything,
甚至连爱因斯坦都想不明白
something even Einstein couldn't figure out.
如果他都想不明白  或许其本身就是错的
Well, if he couldn't figure it out, maybe it's just wrong.
但它那么优雅
But it's so elegant.
我是说  听着  弦理论假定
I mean, look, string theory posits
我们在三维空间看见的基本粒子
that the fundamental particles we see in three dimensions
其实是嵌在多维时空的弦
are actually strings embedded in multidimensional space-time.
有意思
Interesting.
所以那就是说...
So that would mean...
那个...
that...
该配合我的演出你视而不见
Can't do this by myself, buddy.
你在搞什么鬼
What is happening?
我试着尽量不吵醒你
I was trying not to wake you.
成功了吗
Did it work?
抱歉
Sorry.
我刚意识到
I just realized,
现在我不组乐队了
now that I'm not in the band,
我可以专注搞我自己的音乐了
I can focus on my own music.
就是单飞啊
You know? Go solo.
你说你是暂别乐队
You said you were taking a break from the band
好照顾我和宝宝
to help with me and the baby.
对啊  还有写一出宇航员音乐剧
Yes, and write an astronaut musical.
想象一下  幕布拉开
Picture this. The curtain opens.
一位宇航员独自飘浮在
There's a lone astronaut floating
漆黑的太空
in the inky blackness of space.
或许有各种线  或许有雾
Maybe wires, maybe fog.
这交给导演去想吧
I'll let the director figure that out.
♪ 真不知道何时 ♪
♪ I really don't know when ♪
♪ 我会缺氧而...死 ♪
♪ I'll run out of oxy... gen. ♪
好消息  我重回乐队了
Good news! I'm back in the band!
伯纳黛特不介意了吗
So, Bernadette doesn't mind?
是她提议让我回来的
It was her idea!
所以这有点像吉他弦
So it's sort of like a guitar string,
但它不会发出真正的声音
but instead of making an actual sound,
每一次振动是一种不同的粒子
each vibration is a different particle.
完全正确  当你在11维空间弹时
Precisely. And when you express it in 11 dimensions,
爱因斯坦的相对论方程会出现
Einstein's relativity equations pop out.
那听起来像是巧合吗
Does that sound like a coincidence?
-不像  -对
- It does not. - Yup.
我就是这么想的
That's what I think.
所以我们成功了吗  我们刚是解出了弦理论吗
So, so, did we do it? Did we just solve string theory?
我不想打击你的热情
I appreciate your enthusiasm,
但这可不是我们
but this is not the sort of thing
一晚上就能想明白的事情
we can figure out in a night.
人们研究了好几十年都没有突破呢
People have been stuck on this for decades.
几十年  太扯了吧
Well, decades? Really?
不就是一根弦吗  能有多难啊
It's-it's a string. How hard can it be?
它是直的  循环的
It's straight, it's in a loop,
跟其他弦打结系在一起
it gets knotted up with other strings. Uh...
其实超过四维后
Well, actually there are no knots
任何事物不可能存在结点
in anything greater than four dimensions.
除非...
Ooh, unless
我们绕过这一点  把结点看成片状
we get around that by considering them as sheets.
拓扑地来说
You know, topologically speaking,
那就有很多有趣的可能性了
that has a lot of interesting possibilities.
瞧  我花了多长时间  有一分钟吗
See? How long did that take me, like a minute?
我以为你去给我们带饭了呢
Thought you were getting us dinner.
抱歉  我在谢尔顿家待了一阵
Sorry. I had to stop at Sheldon's
帮忙他解决弦理论
and help him solve string theory.
什么
What?
是啊  结果发现答案是结点
Yeah, turns out the answer's knots.
想法挺可爱  但超过四维后
That's cute, but you can't have knots
不可能存在结点
in more than four dimensions.
如果你将其看成片状就存在啊
Mm, you can if you consider them sheets.
晚安啦
Good night.
各位好  我的希伯来弟和希伯来妹
What up, my Hebrews and She-brews?!
我们是月球足迹乐队
We are Footprints on the Moon.
托比  今天你成年了
Toby, today you are a man,
今后你会在生活中面临很多障碍
and you will face many obstacles in life.
有一些障碍会让你觉得犹如巨石
And some of those obstacles are gonna feel like boulders.
第一首歌是关于电影史上
This first song is about the greatest boulder
最伟大的巨石
in the history of cinema.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
♪ 秘鲁深处  独守古庙 ♪
♪ Alone in my temple in the middle of Peru ♪
♪ 巨石如我  无事可做 ♪
♪ A giant stone ball with nothing much to do ♪
♪ 谁敢偷我神像 ♪
♪ But if you steal my idol ♪
♪ 直接把你压扁 ♪
♪ I will roll right over you ♪
♪ 因为我是六吨重的花岗岩 ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm six tons of granite  ♪
♪ 和云母片岩 ♪
♪ And micaceous schist ♪
♪ 没错  六吨重的花岗岩 ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm six tons of granite and ♪
♪ 和云母片岩 ♪
♪ Micaceous schist ♪
♪ 我要压碎你  我要碾扁你 ♪
♪ I'm gonna crush you, I'm gonna mush you ♪
♪ 你偷我神像  你尸体已凉 ♪
♪ You took my idol, I'm homicidal ♪
♪ 我要把你碾得肝脑涂地 ♪
♪ Gonna roll over you till your brains come out ♪
♪ 压得你骨头粉碎  血肉横飞 ♪
♪ And your bones will crunch and your blood will spout! ♪
我不仅仅是块石头  宝贝
I'm not just a rock, baby,
我还是块巨石
I'm also a boulder.
♪ 因为我是六吨重的花岗岩 ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm six tons of granite  ♪
♪ 和云母片岩 ♪
♪ Micaceous schist ♪
♪ 没错  六吨重的花岗岩 ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm six tons of granite and ♪
♪ 和云母片岩 ♪
♪ Micaceous schist ♪